The incredible true story of gold medal champion Jesse Owens
Race is a drama, history film directed by Stephen Hopkins.
Based on the story of Jesse Owens, the athlete whose quest to become the greatest track and field athlete in history thrusts him
onto the world stage of the 1936 Olympics, where he faces off against Adolf Hitler's vision of Aryan supremacy.
Jesse Owens, played by Stephan James.
Larry Snyder, played by Jason Sudeikis.
Dave Albritton, played by Eli Goree.
Ruth Solomon, played by Shanice Banton.
Leni Riefenstahl, played by Carice van Houten.
Avery Brundage, played by Jeremy Irons.
Race is a 2016 biographical sports drama film about African-American athlete Jesse Owens,
who won a record-breaking four gold medals at the 1936 Berlin Olympic Games.
Directed by Stephen Hopkins and written by Joe Shrapnel and Anna Waterhouse, the film stars Stephan James
as Owens, and co-stars Jason Sudeikis, Jeremy Irons, William Hurt and Carice van Houten.
It is a co-production of Canada, Germany and France.
Principal photography began on 24 July 2014, in Montreal, Canada.
Forecast Pictures, Solofilms and Trinity Race produced the film, supported by the Owens
family, the Jesse Owens Foundation, the Jesse Owens Trust and the Luminary Group.
The film was a commercial success and received mixed to positive reviews,
winning four Canadian Screen Awards, including Best Actor for James.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, sports,
olympic games, biography, historical figure.
The tone is emotional.